Reuben Hawthorne-Jensen

Full Stack Developer | Te Whanganui-a-tara (Wellington), Aotearoa New Zealand Citizen



Kia ora! I'm Reuben, a full-stack developer based in Pōneke. My tech journey has been one of incremental immersion. I wrote my first 'Hello World' application at the age of 8 years old in C++ with the help of my dad. Following a brief 15+ year hiatus, I rediscovered my techy roots a few years back and coding is now a central part of my life.

While I have spent most of my career in the sales, communications and marketing space, I have always found myself drawn to understand the inner workings of the tools I was using every day. This curiosity inevitably lead me to start seriously learning to code around two years ago, starting with simple tweaks to websites for marketing and SEO purposes. From there I moved onto a few online courses and began working on my own projects, with a touch of freelance web development here and there. My experience covers not only full-stack development but includes project management, impeccable communication skills and extensive stakeholder management, to name a few. I'm excited to join your team and build some great things together.

What I'm working on right now

My wife is plagued by an issue for which few good solutions exist, and I am sure she is not alone. That is, deciding which outfit to wear each day. I set out to build a simple application to help her decide. The application allows the user to catalogue their wardrobe, and build digital outfits for any occasion. It is a React/Redux front end with Ruby on Rails behind the scenes. You can read more about this project and check out the GitHub repo here

Tech stack (years experience)

- TypeScript/JavaScript (2+)
- Node.js (2+)
- Express (2+)
- SQL (SQLite3, PostgreSQL)
 (2+)
- Ruby on Rails (< 1)
- NoSQL (MongoDB) (1+)
- HTML/CSS/SASS (5+)
- Docker/Dokku (< 1)
- AWS (< 1)
- Git (2+)

Soft Skills

- Written/Verbal
 Communication
- Giving and receiving feedback
- Pair-programming
- Project management
- Stakeholder management
- Agile/Scrum

Experience

Full stack developer (student) | Dev Academy Aotearoa - Jan 2023 - April 2023

Tech used: TypeScript/JavaScript, React, Redux, Node.js, SQL, Git, Stripe, Dokku

- After coding in relative isolation for a couple of years, I felt that I was missing a piece of the
 puzzle. I could build a working app, but I had no experience in a real, collaborative dev team. I
 decided to enrol in Dev Academy to refine my skill set and get practical guidance on how the
 tech industry works in Aotearoa.
- Amongst the many projects I worked on across the 17-week course, I'm most proud of our final project. An app inspired by my real-world challenge of managing subscriptions for my community kickboxing club. Read more about the project here.

Website Development | Freelance - Jan 2020 - Present

Tech used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP (WordPress), Twig (Craft CMS), DNS

 I provide full-stack web design, build and deployment for clients (primarily WordPress and Craft CMS) along with managing DNS records for client sites and support with domain authentication for email and third-party apps

Web & Social Media Advisor | NZEI Te Riu Roa - November 2021 - February 2023

Tech used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP (WordPress), DNS

- I managed a major redesign of NZEI Te Riu Roa's website, which took seven legacy web properties and combined them into one, purpose-built website to support the union's work
- I supported organising and campaign activities with digital media (web, email, social media) and consulted on digital and content strategy
- I worked on minor front-end features, such as responsive header layouts, template modifications, and simple calculators (JavaScript, PHP)
- I consulted on the parallel CRM project for the union, specifically on the points where the CRM would intersect with the new website

Marketing Executive | Storbie - May 2020 - October 2021

Tech used: JavaScript, CSHTML, SCSS, ASP.Net MVC, Visual Studio IDE

- I handled maintenance work for the old Storbie website, built on the ASP.NET framework, in CSHTML, SASS and JavaScript
- I managed the project to rebuild Storbie's website on Umbraco CMS, working collaboratively with in-house designers and developers.
- I developed front-end features for the new website including the pricing page, feature grid and an automated pop-up for lead capture.
- I was responsible for the end-to-end planning, management and implementation of Storbie's marketing strategy.

Marketing Coordinator | Creative HQ - May 2019 - June 2020

Tech used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, WordPress (no-code)

- I managed the websites for Creative HQ's three main brands (CHQ, Lightning Lab and GovTech)
- Planning, implementation and training (internal and external) of digital tools to enable the delivery of digital workshops during the level 4 lockdown in 2020
- I took part in agile rituals through supporting workshops and design sprints for CHQ clients

Account Executive | Isentia - January 2018 - May 2019

Tech used: VisualBasic (Microsoft Office)

- Providing technical support and guidance to maximise the value of Isentia's products
- Working with clients to understand their needs, optimise their service
- Strategic relationship management with a focus on growth opportunities within client accounts

Full work history available on request

Qualifications

 Certificate in Applied Software Development

> Dev Academy Aotearoa Jan 2023 - April 2023

• Bachelor of Commerce in Marketing Victoria University of Wellington 2014–2017 Bachelor of Arts in Media Studies and Theatre

Victoria University of Wellington 2014–2017

- IC Agile Certified Professional Awarded May 2022
- Certificate in Te Reo Māori (level 3)

 Te Wānanga o Raukawa

Community Involvement

• Executive Board Member | Wellington Thai Boxing

2021 - Present

I work with the two other ELT members to handle club logistics and admin, including updating the website and social media profiles, ordering new gear and organising events.

• Volunteer Muay Thai Trainer | Wellington Thai Boxing

2020 - Present

Teaching Muay Thai classes to students with a range of skill levels from beginners to fighters.

References available on request